## SHASHANK RAVIKUMAR

Ilford, Essex m: 07858280680 shashank201011@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/shashank-ravikumar

### **OBJECTIVE**

To advance my career with a leading organisation that will utilise my extensive computer science knowledge while also allowing me to develop further as a professional

Creative, detail-oriented Computer Science graduate with the academic qualifications and practical experiences to conceive, design and execute web apps and other solutions on time and within project parameters. Possess a solid foundation in coding languages, software tools, human-computer interaction, and wireframe development. Partner with high-powered design teams to contribute to product development and implementation strategy. Outstanding communicator and able to collect stakeholder and user requirements before translating them into exceptionally designed assets. Qualifications include a Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and technical proficiencies across a wide range of tools.

#### **CORE COMPETENCIES**

- Critical Analysis
  Multi-Laurend Communication
- Multi-Layered Communication
- Cross-Functional Collaboration
- Database Systems
- UX/UI Design
- Conceptualisation

- Customer Service
- Needs Assessment
- Problem Solving

## **EDUCATION AND CREDENTIALS**

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE (B.Sc.) IN COMPUTER SCIENCE, SEPTEMBER 2017 TO JULY 2020

University of East Anglia, Norwich Research Park, Norwich, NR4 7TJ, UK

**Relevant Coursework:** Human-Computer interaction (Can create wireframes at various levels of Fidelity prototypes), Networks, Database Systems

**Final Year Project:** Developed "Catching the phish," a game-based cybersecurity system to help improve the user's awareness regarding cybersecurity and specifically phishing. Improved user awareness by testing them in a variety of email-based simulations to help them successfully identify simulated malicious phishing attempts. This was then developed, tested, cleared for ethics and fully deployed with the use of GitHub repository and Trello for saving and documentation of project progression. The project code can be accessed here: https://github.com/offbr0wn/Phising-Awareness-Website

<u>UDEMY UX/UI COURSE IN USER EXPERIENCE DESIGN ESSENTIALS, NOVEMBER 2020 TO JANUARY 2021</u> *Udemy Inc.* 

Learned fundamentals of UX Design, from changing icon sizes to building a fully visualised prototype.

GCE A LEVEL, SEPTEMBER 2015 TO JULY 2017

Relevant Coursework: Mathematics (B) Physics (C) BTEC Business (DD\*)

GCSE's, SEPTEMBER 2010 TO JULY 2015

Relevant Coursework: 8 Subjects A\* – C grades, including English (C) & Maths (B)

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SITEL NHS TRACK AND TRACE, WORK FROM HOME, DECEMBER 2020 - AUGUST 2021

#### **CUSTOMER SALES ADVISOR**

- Providing an excellent customer service experience for our clients
- Solve customer issues with their computers
- Scheduling appointments for clients
- Managing multiple software programs at a time

SHASHANK RAVIKUMAR Page 2

- Kept accurate records of client's interactions
- Determine charges for plans purchased with us or services scheduled

DOMINO'S PIZZA, BARKINGSIDE, ESSEX, MARCH 2020 TO JULY 2020

#### **CUSTOMER SALES REPRESENTATIVE**

• Charted a successful course for customer satisfaction by responding to customer inquiries, resolving concerns, and taking orders in a deadline-drive environment.

- Assisted with food preparation as necessary.
- Ensured customer-facing and other areas were clean and sanitary by organisational and regulatory health standards.
- Utilised Point of Sale system to allow customers to place orders both through phone and in-store.

ROMFORD MAIL CENTRE, LONDON, UK, JULY 2019 TO DECEMBER 2019

#### **ROYAL MAIL SORTER**

- Organised the sorting of mail, packets, parcels, and other deliverable items; utilised a parcel sorting machine.
- Ensured accurate, efficient, and compliant separation of 1st Class and 2nd Class mail.
- Oversaw categorisation of items (Standard, Next Day, Signed For, Recorded).
- Aligned item dispatching with the appropriate timetable.
- Performed additional tasks in collaboration with other colleagues as necessary.

BARNARDO'S SHOP, ILFORD, ESSEX, JUNE 2017 TO SEPTEMBER 2017

#### **CUSTOMER SALES ASSISTANT**

- Processed sales and returns and took on administrative tasks such as stocktaking.
- Stock processing and preparation including sorting, steaming and pricing.
- Managed and restocked inventory.
- Deploying exceptional customer service skills and assisted customers with inquiries.

## **AWARDS AND HONOURS**

- National Citizen Service Award (NCS), August 2015
  - Gained leadership skills through team projects.
  - o Bolstered team-working skills by working as a team and communicating together.
  - o Boosted confidence by presenting in front of approximately 100 people.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Coding Languages: Java, JavaScript, Python with Django Framework experience, C++, MySQL, HTML5 & CSS3, React
- **Software:** GitHub, Trello, Microsoft Office (Access, Excel, PowerPoint, Word), Adobe Photoshop and Lightroom, Adobe Premiere Pro, Adobe XD, Figma, Window OS

## **ADDITIONAL INFORMATION**

**Certificates:** Karate, National Citizen Service Award (NCS), Udemy UX/UI Course in User Experience Design Essentials

**Interests:** Exercising, competed in Powerlifting tournaments mixed martial arts, basketball, computer troubleshooting/repair, software installation, smartphone assistance, gaming

Page 3

# **REFERENCES**

Available on request